Data Engineer

Data Engineer

San Francisco, CA

Data engineer with 3+ years of experience at a high-volume e-commerce company. Started career in operations and gradually developed coding skills to production-level quality. Focused on using my unique background and data expertise to build and support amazing products.

Work Experience

Data Engineer

Zinio LLC - San Francisco, CA August 2015 to December 2018

- Provided technical expertise to marketing, business intelligence teams on strategies for identifying and grouping user interactivity and sales data; wrote ad-hoc queries for the diverse needs internal users.
- Maintained data structures and integrity across all repositories; wrote programs to identify and correct anomalies.
- Designed and implemented ETL jobs for marketing and analytics via stored procedures and Talend ETL tool.
- Worked closely with marketing team to identify business requirements, design and implement all data structures and reoccurring queries in Oracle Responsys marketing database.
- Provided administrative support for SQL Server production database.
- Worked closely with project manager on major, year-long cross-platform migration. This included generating extensive documentation on existing stored procedures, creating a full data dictionary and mapping data structures into the new database.
- Responsible for maintaining Google Analytics platform.
- Utilized TSQL, MSSQL, MySQL, PL/SQL, Python.

Fulfillment Manager - E-Commerce

Zinio LLC - San Francisco, CA

November 2013 to July 2015

- Managed day-to-day operations and quality control of in-house digital delivery system including labels, reporting, data imports, and data processing. Managed data exports for client businesses and third-party fulfillment houses.
- Identified and monitored KPIs, working closely with IT and engineering teams to improve existing systems and implement performance fixes.
- Designed and helped implement full fulfillment lifecycle tracking procedures.
- Managed FTP for third-party delivery data imports.

Education

Bachelor of Arts in Philosophy Miami University Oxford, OH May 2008 Skills

SQL Programming (Less than 1 year), ETL (Less than 1 year), Oracle Responsys (Less than 1 year), Data Analysis (Less than 1 year), Database Administration (Less than 1 year), Google Analytics (Less than 1 year)

Certifications

Oracle Responsys Cloud Implementation Specialist April 2017 to Present